Mss.B.Sh86
American Philosophical Society
Richard Harrison Shryock papers, [ca. 1918-1972]
Circa 1918-1972
Mss.B.Sh86
American Philosophical Society
23.0 Linear feet Ca. 20,000 items
This collection contains primarily professional correspondence and papers, but there is substantial material concerning Shryock family history. Most of the collection relates to Shryock's intellectual and social life at the University of Pennsylvania, Duke University, and Johns Hopkins University-- institutions where he made contributions as a professor of history and especially as a medical historian.
Ca. 20,000 items, 23 linear feet.
Shryock, Richard Harrison, 1893-1972
Box 1-46
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Presented by Rheva O. Shryock and accessioned, 05/05/1973 (1973 2293ms). See in-house shelf list for additional accession numbers and dates.
Biographical/Historical note
Richard Harrison Shryock was a medical historian and was Librarian of the American Philosophical Society from 1958 to 1965.
American Association for the History of Medicine.; American Association of University Professors.; American Council of Learned Societies.; American Philosophical Society. Library.; Bowman, Isaiah, 1878-1950; Boyd, Julian Charles, 1931-2005; Bradley, Sculley, 1897-; Bridenbaugh, Carl, 1903-1992; Butterfield, L. H., (Lyman Henry), 1909-; Carmichael, Leonard, 1898-1973; Cochran, Thomas Childs, 1902-; Cohen, I. Bernard, 1914-2003; Cohn, Alfred E., (Alfred Einstein), 1879-1957; Curti, Merle Eugene, 1897-; Duke University -- Faculty.; Dupree, A. Hunter; Fulton, John F., (John Farquhar), 1899-1960; Garrison, Fielding H., (Fielding Hudson), 1870-1935; Harrison, Ross G., (Ross Granville), 1870-1959; Hindle, Brooke, 1918-2001; Historical Society of Pennsylvania.; Johns Hopkins University. Faculty.; Knopf, Alfred A., 1892-1984; Kollmorgen, Walter Martin, 1907-; Koyré, Alexandre, 1892-1964; Leake, Chauncey Depew,1896-; Long, Esmond R., (Esmond Ray), 1890-; Marshall, John; Nichols, Roy F., (Roy Franklin), 1896-1973; Olmsted, John W.; Pierson, George Wilson, 1904-; Pogo, Alexander, 1893-; Shryock family.; Sigerist, Henry E., (Henry Ernest), 1891-1957; Temkin, Owsei, 1902-; University of Pennsylvania. Faculty.; Viets, Henry R., (Henry Rouse), 1890-1969; Historians.; History -- Study and teaching.; Medicine -- History.; Medicine -- United States.
- Photographs, 25.0 Photograph(s); The following represent a sample of photographs from the Richard Harrison Shryock papers.
  - John Knight Shryock, 1906, 1.0 Photograph(s); Formal portrait of John Knight Shryock.
  - "Saddle Rock": Shryock child and mother [?], sitting, full length, informal portrait, 1892, August; 1.0 Photograph(s); View of child and woman seated outside on rock, hills and structure in background.
  - Shryock child and mother [?], "bound for the beach" standing, full length, informal portrait, 1892, August; 1.0 Photograph(s); Child and woman standing outside on steps, house in background.
  - Richard Harrison Shryock, four months old, 1893, August; 1.0 Photograph(s); View of Shryock, as a baby, wrapped in blanket.
  - Richard Harrison Shryock at a young age, posed for formal photograph, ca. 1900; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length view of Shryock, at a young age, looking into a soap carton, wearing a hat.
  - Richard Harrison Shryock, at a young age, with John K. and James N. Shryock, ca. 1898; 1.0 Photograph(s); Shryock and brothers at young age sitting on rock, water in background.
  - Richard Henry Shryock, 3/4 length, standing, formal portrait, 1904; 1.0 Photograph(s); Shryock, age eleven, holding book and wearing choir gown.
  - Brotherhood of St. Andrew Reunion, Church of the Incarnation, Philadelphia, ca. 1925; 1.0 Photograph(s); Group portrait of men sitting and standing.
  - Richard Henry Shryock, 3/4, sitting, formal portrait, ca. 1915; 1.0 Photograph(s); Half length view of Shryock seated in wooden chair.
  - Richard Harrison Shryock and Mrs. Shryock (?) standing outside, Wissahickon, Pennsylvania, ca. 1920; 1.0 Photograph(s); Half length view of man and woman standing outside, rocks and plants in background.
  - Richard Harrison Shryock, seated holding book, n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); Half lenght, 3/4 view portrait of Shryock, seated, holding a book.
  - Richard Harrison Shryock, formal portrait, n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); Formal portrait of Shryock.
  - Richard Harrison Shrock, at the Library of Congress, 1929, 1.0 Photograph(s); Half length portrait of Shryock, seated, bookcases in background.
  - Richard Harrison Shryock (?), standing outside, leaning against rock, 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length view of man standing outside, holding hat, leaning against rock.
  - John Knight Shryock, Richard Harrison Shryock, and Jannes Noble Shryock, 3/4 profile,full length, sitting, informal portrait, ca. 1928; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length view of three men sitting on rock, water and boat in background.
    Related Archival Materials note
    Campanion photo available of same three subjects as children on same rock, thirty years previous. See APSimg7603.
  - John Knight Shryock, Richard Harrison Shryock, and Jannes Noble Shryock, half length, sitting, formal portrait, ca. 1897; 1.0 Photograph(s); Formal group portrait.
  - Richard Harrison Shryock standing outside near tree and seated people, 1.0 Photograph(s); View of Shyrock, seated people in forefront. Possibily Univeristy of Pennsylvania campus.
  - George W. Corner, Richard H. Shryock, Charles Coutry, and unidentified man, half length, informal, seated at Wellcome Library, London, August, 1967, Conference on Medical History, 1967, August; 1.0 Photograph(s); View of four men seated at desk, wall of photographs in background.
  - Howard Lewis, Oliver Wendell Holmes, Richard Shryock, Charles Blitzer, Joseph Henry Papers Meeting, Washington, 10 May 1968, 1968 May 10; 1.0 Photograph(s); View of four men sitting at table, informal, one woman in foreground writing.
  - Richard H. Shryock, Lewis Deschler, John Nicholas Brown, Wilmarth Sheldon Lewis, Catherine Drinker Bowen, Leonard Carmichael, David Finley, John Walker, and Frederick Todd seated and standing at the first meeting at Smithsonian Institute, D.C., 1963, 1.0 Photograph(s); Group portrait taken in board room.
  - Richard Harrison Shryock and Gertrude Hess (?), standing on APS steps, 1961 May 29; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full lenght view of Shryock and Hess standing on the American Philosophical Society Library steps.
  - Lancaster, formal portrait, n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); Portrait of Lancaster, professor of political science.
  - Man standing on porch, 'a true'fish-story', 1890 September 2; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length view of unidentified man with mustache standing outside, holding a fish on a hook.; Handwritten note on album page beneath photograph: "A true 'fish story.'" Sept. 2, 1890.
  - Rev. R. M. Chipman (?), seated, reading book, n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); Chipman seated reading book, unidentified woman seated in chair.
  - Unidentifed woman and two men, full length, seated on porch "after tennis", 1890 September; 1.0 Photograph(s); Exterior view of two men and one woman, sitting outside.